Register of the Eric Voegelin papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and Writings, 1921-1987
  - Order and History, Vol.II: The World of the Polis, 1957
    - Reviews
      - Becker, L. D., "Eric Voegelin's Conception of Tragedy. A Brief Study of Moby Dick,", 1967 May (Box-folder 67: 4)
    - German translation of the introduction (Peter J. Opitz) (Box-folder 67: 5)
  - Order and History, Vol.III: Plato and Aristotle, 1957
    - Typescript (Box-folder 67: 6-7)
    - Typescript (Box-folder 68: 1)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 68: 2)
    - Reviews (Box-folder 68: 3)
  - "Ergebnisse der klassischen Staatstheorie,", 1957 January 14 (Box-folder 68: 4)
    Speech, Frankfurt, West Germany. Outline
  - "Causes of Revolutionary Unrest in the Modern World,", 1957 May 6 (Box-folder 68: 5)
    Speech (and seminar entitled "The Breakdown of Ideologies" on 6-7 May), College of Business Administration, University of Georgia, Athens, Georgia. Outline and correspondence with Gregor Sebba
  - "Mankind and History,", 1957 May 8 (Box-folder 68: 6)
    Speech, Emory University, Georgia. Correspondence with Leroy E. Loemker
  - "Empire and Christianity,", circa 1958 (Box-folder 68: 7)
    Outline for the projected Vol.IV of Order and History, as originally laid out in Vol.I
  - "Der Prophet Elias," Hochland, 1958 (Box-folder 68: 8)
    Galley proofs and review
  - "Religion und politische Ordnung in den Vereinigten Staaten,", 1958 May 29 (Box-folder 68: 9)
    Speech, Deutsche Gesellschaft für Amerikastudien, Mainz, West Germany. Notes, outline, and correspondence with Walther Fischer
  - "Die ökumenischen Reiche,", 1958 June 27 (Box-folder 68: 10)
    Speech, Institut für Politische Wissenschaft an der Universität Heidelberg, West Germany. Correspondence with Carl J. Friedrich
  - "Religion und politische Ordnung in den Vereinigten Staaten,", 1958 July 3 (Box-folder 68: 11)
    Speech, Münchner Amerika-Haus, Munich. Clipping and letter from a member of the audience. See speech of 29 May 1958 for outline
  - Conférence contribution, L'Histoire et ses Interprétations, Cerisy-La-Salle, France, 1958 July 10-20 (Box-folder 68: 12)
    Clipping and correspondence with Marc Heurgon
  - "Die alten Weltreiche: Struktur und Ideen,", 1958 November 12 (Box-folder 68: 13)
    Speech, Joachim-Jungius Gesellschaft, Hamburg, West Germany. Correspondence with Otto Brunner and Irmgard Pracht
  - Wissenschaft, Politik und Gnosis, 1959
    - Typescript
      - 1958 (Box-folder 68: 14)
      - 1959 (Box-folder 68: 15-16)
    - Galley proofs (Box-folder 68: 17)
    - Printed copy of introduction (excerpt) (Box-folder 68: 18)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 68: 19)
    - Reviews (Box-folder 69: 1)
    - English translation, (William J. Fitzpatrick), 1968
      - Typescript (Box-folder 69: 2)
        Includes letters from William J. Fitzpatrick and Henry Regnery
      - Galley proofs (Box-folder 69: 3)
      - Reviews (Box-folder 69: 4)
  - "Diskussionsbereitschaft,", 1959 February 2 (Box-folder 69: 5)
    Speech, Schweizerisches Institut für Auslandforschung, Zurich, Switzerland. Outline, typescript, printed copy, and clippings
  - "Demokratie im neuen Europa,", 1959 February 21 (Box-folder 69: 6)
    Speech, Ludwig-Maximilians-Universität München, Munich, West Germany. Typescript, galley proofs, printed copy, and clippings
  - "Der Einzelne in der modernen Massengesellschaft,", 1959 February 23 (Box-folder 69: 7)
    Speech, Münchner Bildungswerk, Munich, West Germany. Outline
  - "Die geistige und politische Zukunft des Westens,", 1959 May 9 (Box-folder 69: 8)
    Speech, Amerikahaus, Munich, West Germany. Outline
  - "Die gnostischen Massenbewegungen,", 1959 July 24 (Box-folder 69: 9)
    Conference paper, Alte Ideologien in einer Neuen Welt, Katholische Junge Mannschaft, Munich, West Germany. Correspondence with Emil Martin
  - "Los movimientos de masas en nuestro tiempo,", 1959 August 11 (Box-folder 69: 10)
    Speech, Internationale Sommeruniversität, Santander, Spain. Correspondence and clippings
  - "Der Zusammenbruch der Ideologien,", 1959 September 17 (Box-folder 69: 11)
    Speech, Wiener Internationale Hochschulkurse an der Universität zu Wien, Vienna, Austria. Outlines and correspondence with Leo Gabriel
  - "In Quest of a Political Philosophy,", 1959 September 25-26
    Paper, Industrial Society and Western Political Dialogue Conference, Rheinfelden, Switzerland
    - Notes and typescript (Box-folder 69: 12)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 69: 13)
    - Clippings (Box-folder 69: 14)
    - Spanish translation entitled "El concepto de la 'buena sociedad'," Cuadernos, January-February 1960 (Box-folder 69: 15)
  - Speech relating to industrial societies, circa 1960 (Box-folder 69: 16)
    Typescript in German
  - "Historiogenesis," Philosophisches Jahrbuch, 1960 (Box-folder 70: 1)
    Notes, typescript, galley proofs, and printed copy
  - "Les mouvements de masse gnostiques à notre époque,", 1960 (Box-folder 70: 2)
    Speech. Typescript
  - "Religionsersatz: Die gnostischen Massenbewegungen unserer Zeit," Wort und Wahrheit, 1960
    - Printed copy (Box-folder 70: 3)
    - English translation entitled "Ersatz Religion: The Gnostic Mass Movements of Our Time," Politeia, 1964 Spring (Box-folder 70: 4)
  - "Der Liberalismus und seine Geschichte,", 1960 January 8
    Speech, Katholische Akademie in Bayern, Munich, West Germany
    - Outline and typescript (Box-folder 70: 5)
    - Galley proofs and clippings (Box-folder 70: 6)
    - Correspondence with Karl Forster and Karl Zemanek (Springer-Verlag) (Box-folder 70: 7)
    - English translation (Mary and Keith Algozin) entitled "Liberalism and Its History," The Review of Politics, 1974 October (Box-folder 70: 8)
  - "Die intellektuelle Verwirrung der deutschen Studenten,", 1960 April 3 (Box-folder 70: 9)
    Conference paper, Staatsbürgerliche Erziehung in Deutschland und USA, Akademie für Politische Bildung, Tutzing, West Germany. Notes and outline. Includes notes and outline for another talk, entitled "Politische Erziehung in der amerikanischen Schule"
  - "Die gnostischen Massenbewegungen,", 1960 April 23 (Box-folder 70: 10)
    Conference paper, Das Problem des Totalen Staates in Unserer Gesellschaft, Hochschule für Politische Bildung, Bad Meinberg, West Germany. Outline, typescript, and correspondence with Dr. Nachtwey
  - "Verantwortung und Freiheit in Wirtschaft und Demokratie,", 1960 May 27 (Box-folder 70: 11)
    Speech, Berliner Kongresshalle, Berlin, West Germany. Outline, typescript, and printed copies
  - Remarks, panel discussion on "Order and History," American Political Science Association, Fifty-sixth Annual Meeting, Statler Hilton Hotel, New York City, 1960 September 9 (Box-folder 70: 12)
    Session account by John C. Jacobs and correspondence with William F. Albright and Thomas I. Cook. Includes paper by William F. Albright
  - "Gnostic Mass Movements,", 1960 October 26 (Box-folder 70: 13)
    Speech, University of Notre Dame, South Bend, Indiana. Outline
  - "Spiritual and Political Future of the West,", 1960 November 2 (Box-folder 70: 14)
    Speech, Woodland Residence, Chicago, Illinois. Outline and correspondence with Paul J. Deck
  - "Experience and Symbolization,", 1960 November 10 (Box-folder 70: 15)
    Speech, University of Illinois, Urbana, Illinois. Outline and correspondence with Paul Diessing
  - "The Breakdown of Ideologies,", 1960 November 16 (Box-folder 70: 16)
  - "Perspectives de la civilisation occidentale,", 1961 (Box-folder 70: 17)
  - "Politische Denkformen in Asien und der Einbruch des Westen,", 1961 (Box-folder 70: 18)
    Speech, Bad Ems, West Germany. Outline, typescript, and correspondence with Wolfgang Hug (Deutsche UNESCO-Kommission)
  - "Experience and Symbolization,", 1961 January 3 (Box-folder 70: 19)
    Paper, Symposium on the Scientific Alternatives to Communist Ideologies, University of Notre Dame, South Bend, Indiana. Notes and account of presentation and discussion
  - Speech, 1961 January 13 (Box-folder 71: 1)
  - Speech, International Relations Inquiry, Georgetown University, Washington, D.C., 1961 February (Box-folder 71: 2)
    Correspondence with Howard R. Penniman
  - "World Empire and the Unity of Mankind,", 1961 March 3 (Box-folder 71: 3)
    Speech, Stevenson Memorial Lecture, London School of Economics and Political Science, London, United Kingdom. Outline, typescript, printed copy, and correspondence
  - "Lebenswerte und Rechtswerte in den modernen Naturrechtstheorien,", 1961 June 3 (Box-folder 71: 4)
    Speech, Walberberger Institut, Bonn, West Germany. Outline and correspondence with P. Leopold Jäger
  - "Was ist 'Politischer Stil'?", 1962 January 30 (Box-folder 71: 5)
    Speech, Akademie für Politische Bildung, Tutzing, West Germany. Outline and clippings
  - Speech, Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, Louisiana, 1962 April 5 (Box-folder 71: 6)
  - "Das Rechte von Natur,", 1962 August 2 (Box-folder 71: 7)
    Conference paper, Das Naturrecht in der Politischen Theorie, Institut für Politische Wissenschaften, Salzburg, Austria. Notes, typescript, printed copy, clipping, and correspondence with Franz-Martin Schmölz. Includes typewritten transcript of discussion
  - "Ewiges Sein in der Zeit,", 1962 October 24
    Speech, VII. Deutscher Kongress für Philosophie, Münster, West Germany
    - Notes, outline, typescript, and correspondence with Joachim Ritter, Ludwig Landgrebe, K. H. Volkmann-Schluck, Franz Wiedmann (Box-folder 71: 8)
    - Correspondence with Erich Dinkler regarding publication in Zeit und Geschichte: Dankesgabe an Rudolf Bultmann Zum 80 Geburtstag and printed copy from 1964. (Box-folder 71: 9)
  - "Vorwort,", 1962 November (Box-folder 71: 10)
    Foreword to Vol.I of Politik und Eschatologie by J. Gebhardt, published by the Geschwister-Scholl-Institut für Politische Wissenschaft (Universität München). Typescript
  - "Ancient Gnosis and Modern Politics,", 1962 November 22 (Box-folder 71: 11)
    Speech, London School of Economics and Political Science, London, United Kingdom. Outline and correspondence with James Henderson, W. S. Collings, Michael J. Oakeshott
  - "Industrial Society in Search of Reason," World Technology and Human Destiny, 1963 (Box-folder 71: 12)
  - "Konzeption gesellschaftlicher Ordnung." Paper, Colloquium, Walter-Raymond-Stiftung, Cologne, West Germany, 1963 January 10-12 (Box-folder 71: 13)
    Outline, typescript, and correspondence with Ernst August Jures
  - "Ist das deutsche Volk reif für die Demokratie?", 1963 January 17 (Box-folder 71: 14)
    Speech, Katholische Akademie in Bayern, Munich, West Germany. Outline, correspondence, and clipping
  - "Weltmann und Gelehrter: Zum 70 Geburtstag Friedrich Engel-Janosi,", 1963 February 16-17 (Box-folder 71: 15)
  - "The Configuration of History,", 1963 April 14 (Box-folder 71: 16)
    Speech and interchange with Arnold J. Toynbee on "The Philosophy of History," Grinnell College, Grinnell, Iowa. Notes, outline, typescript, clipping, and correspondence with Paul G. Kuntz, Winston L. King, William S. Vanderpool. Includes statements by and on Arnold J. Toynbee
  - "Wandlungen der modernen Industriegesellschaft in den Vereinigten Staaten und ihre Rückwirkungen auf Europa,", 1963 May 23 (Box-folder 71: 17)
    Speech, Hotel Regina, Munich, West Germany. Outline and typescript
  - "Der Mensch in Gesellschaft und Geschichte,", 1963 September 3 (Box-folder 71: 18)
    Speech, Institut für Politische Wissenschaften, Salzburg, Austria. Outline, typescript, printed copy, and clipping
  - "Philosophie und Humanität,", 1963 October 19 (Box-folder 72: 1)
    Speech, Katholische Akademie in Bayern, Munich, West Germany. Notes and outline
  - "Demokratie und Industriegesellschaft," Veröffentlichungen der Walter-Raymond-Stiftung, 1964 (Box-folder 72: 2)
  - "Die Grösse Max Webers,", 1964 June 23 (Box-folder 72: 3)
    Speech, Die Ludwig- Maximilians-Universität München, Munich, West Germany. Notes, outline, typescript, and clippings
  - "Versuch zu einer Philosophie der Geschichte,", 1964 August 7 (Box-folder 72: 4)
    Speech, Institut für Politische Wissenschaften, Salzburg, Austria. Discussion notes and correspondence
  - "Political Reality,", 1964 November (Box-folder 72: 5)
    Speech, University of Massachusetts at Amherst, Massachusetts. Outline
  - "Was ist Natur?" Historica, 1965 (Box-folder 72: 6)
  - "The Quest of the Ground,", 1965 January 8 (Box-folder 72: 7)
    Speech, Duke University, Durham, North Carolina. Outline
  - "Immortality: Experience and Symbol,", 1965 January 14 (Box-folder 72: 8)
    Speech, Ingersoll Lecture on Immortality, Harvard Divinity School, Cambridge, Massachusetts. Outline, typescript, printed copy, and correspondence with Samuel H. Miller
  - "The Quest of the Ground,", 1965 March 25 (Box-folder 72: 9)
    Speech, Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, Louisiana. Outline
  - "Was ist politische Realität?", 9 June 1965 (Box-folder 72: 10)
    Conference paper, Akademie für Politische Bildung, Tutzing, West Germany. Notes, typescript, printed copy, and discussion notes
  - "Die deutsche Universität und die Ordnung der deutschen Gesellschaft,", 1965 December 16
    Speech, Universität München, Munich, West Germany
    - Notes, typescript, printed copy, clipping, and correspondence with Hans Maier and Ludwig Kotter (Box-folder 72: 11)
    - English translation (Russell Nieli, assisted by Paul Caringella, Thomas Hollweck, and Wolfgang Mann) entitled "The German University and the Order of German Society: A Reconsideration of the Nazi Era," The Intercollegiate Review, 1985 Spring/Summer (Box-folder 72: 12)
  - Anamnesis: Zur Theorie der Geschichte und Politik, 1966
    - Notes (Box-folder 72: 13)
    - Holograph (Box-folder 72: 14)
    - Typescript (Box-folder 72: 15)
    - Typescript (Box-folder 73: 1-2)
    - Page proofs (Box-folder 73: 3)
    - English translation, (Gerhart Niemeyer), 1978
      - Reviews (Box-folder 73: 4)
      - Typescript of chapter 1 ("Remembrance of Things Past," a new essay which replaced the foreword) and chapter 3 (Box-folder 73: 5)
        Includes correspondence with Gerhart Niemeyer
      - Correspondence with Mark O'Connell, production editor (Box-folder 73: 6)
        See also CORRESPONDENCE, University of Notre Dame Press
      - Reviews
        - General (Box-folder 73: 7)
        - Dorter, Kenneth (Box-folder 73: 8)
      - Typescript and printed copy of "Consciousness and Order: 'Foreword' to Anamnesis (1966)," Logos, 1983 (Box-folder 73: 9)
        This translation of the foreword was done by Eric Voegelin especially for Logos
  - Plato, 1966 (Box-folder 73: 10)
    Announcement
  - "Bewusstsein vom Grund,", 1966 April 27 (Box-folder 73: 11)
    Speech, Vienna, Austria. Outline
  - "Universität und Offentlichkeit," Wort und Wahrheit, 1966 August/September (Box-folder 73: 12)
  - "Emigration - Heimkehr aus dem Schattenreich,", 1966 October 13 (Box-folder 73: 13)
    Conference paper, Emigration - Verrat an Deutschland?, Akademie für Politische Bildung, Tutzing, West Germany. Notes, outline, and clippings
  - "A Typology of Revolution,", 1967 January 18 (Box-folder 73: 14)
    Research Seminar on Revolution, Centre of Near and Middle Eastern Studies, University of London, London, United Kingdom. Outline
  - "On Debate and Existence," The Intercollegiate Review, 1967 March/April (Box-folder 73: 15)
  - "The Drama of Humanity,", 1967 April 17-20
    Series of three speeches, entitled "Man in the Cosmos," "The Epiphany of Man," and "The Revolt of Man," Walter Turner Candler Lectures, Emory University, Atlanta, Georgia
    - Notes (Box-folder 74: 1)
    - Outline, typescript, clippings, and correspondence with Gregor Sebba (Box-folder 74: 2)
  - "Apocalyptic Revolution,", 1967 May 18 (Box-folder 74: 3)
    Speech, Chamber of Commerce, Milan, Italy. Typescript and correspondence with Unione Italiana per il Progresso della Cultura - Comitato di Milano
  - Speech relating to the "Kim Case," Munich, West Germany, 1967 July 11 (Box-folder 74: 4)
    Research material, notes, typescript, and correspondence with Franz Joseph Meier, Ludwig Kotter, Oskar Mayer, regarding the disappearance of Taekhoan Kim, a South Korean student at the Geschwister-Scholl-Institut für Politische Wissenschaft (Universität München)
  - "Religion and the Free Society,", 1967 October 6 (Box-folder 74: 5)
    Speech, Philadelphia Society, New York City. Outline and correspondence with Don Lipsett
  - "The Quest of the Ground,", 1967 October 10 (Box-folder 74: 6)
    Speech, Syracuse University, Syracuse, New York. Outline
  - "Historiogenesis,", circa 1968 (Box-folder 74: 7)
    Chapter 1 of one of the attempts to start Vol.IV of Order and History. Typescript. Pages 10-81 entitled "Anxiety and Reason"
  - "What Is History?", circa 1968 (Box-folder 74: 8)
    Chapter 1 of one of the attempts to start Vol.IV of Order and History. Typescript. See also Notes and research material, undated, Weltalter; and "The State of Philosophy," undated
  - "The German Malaise,", 1968 February 9 (Box-folder 74: 9)
    Speech, Duke University, Durham, North Carolina. Outline and correspondence with John H. Hallowell
  - "Equivalences of Experience and Symbolization in History,", 1968 October 4
    Conference paper, Valori Permanenti nel Divenire Storico, Istituto Accademico di Roma, Rome, Italy
    - Typescript (Box-folder 74: 10)
    - Summary (in English, as well as in French and Italian) (Box-folder 74: 11)
    - Correspondence and clipping (Box-folder 74: 12)
  - "History and Gnosis," The Old Testament and Christian Faith, 1969 (Box-folder 75: 1)
  - "The Moving Soul,", 1969
    - Notes (Box-folder 75: 2)
    - Typescript (Box-folder 75: 3)
    - Correspondence with Fritz Wagner, Walter Rollwagen, G. J. Whitrow, Henry Margenau, Manfred Henningsen (Box-folder 75: 4)
  - "Sozialkrise und Entfremdung,", 1969 January 23 (Box-folder 75: 5)
    Speech, Lessing Gesellschaft Nürnberg zur Förderung der Toleranz, Nuremberg, West Germany. Clipping and correspondence with Herta Bellwinkel
  - "Die Dummköpfe von links und rechts," AZ-Feuilleton, 1969 February 15-16 (Box-folder 75: 6)
    Interview relating to Eric Voegelin's experiences in Germany and with the German university system (since 1958). Printed copy
  - "The Transformation of Philosophy in our Time,", 1969 Apri 8 (Box-folder 75: 7)
    Speech, Stanford University, Stanford, California. Outline and correspondence with Jim Hobson
  - "In Search of Order,", 1969 May 13 (Box-folder 75: 8)
    Speech, East Texas State University, Commerce, Texas. Mimeographed announcement
  - "On Hegel--A Study in Sorcery,", 1969 September 4
    Conference paper, International Society for the Study of Time, Oberwolfach, West Germany
    - Typescript (Box-folder 75: 9-10)
    - Galley proofs and printed copy, Studium Generale, No. 24, 1971 (Box-folder 75: 11)
    - Correspondence with J. T. Fraser, Gregor Sebba, S. G. F. Brandon, Francis C. Haber, Wilfred Cantwell Smith, E. H. Gombrich, G. J. Whitrow, Jacob Taubes, Studium Generale (Springer-Verlag), Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft (Müller-Daehn) (Box-folder 76: 1)
  - "Aeschylus, Tragedy, and History,", 1969 November 19 (Box-folder 76: 2)
    Speech, Reed College, Portland, Oregon. Correspondence with Volney Gay
  - "Centers of Experience in Reality,", circa 1970 (Box-folder 76: 3)
  - Outlines, 1970s (Box-folder 76: 4)
  - "The Eclipse of Reality," Phenomenology and Social Reality, 1970 (Box-folder 76: 5)
    Research material; notes; typescript of full manuscript, of which only the first part was published; and printed copy
  - "The Hope of the Gospels and the Hope of Culture,", 1970 February 26 (Box-folder 76: 6)
    Speech, University of Dallas Station, Texas. Correspondence with Leo Paul S. de Alvarez
  - "The Gospel and Culture,", 1970 April 7
    Speech, Pittsburgh Festival on the Gospels, Pittsburgh Theological Seminary, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania
    - Notes (Box-folder 76: 7)
    - Outline and typescript (Box-folder 76: 8)
    - Printed copy, Jesus and Man's Hope, Vol.II, 1971 (Box-folder 76: 9)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 76: 10)
  - "Apocalypse and Revolution,", 1970 November 10 (Box-folder 76: 11)
    Speech (and seminar on Hegel and Marx on November 11), Loyola College, Montreal, Canada. Correspondence with Malcolm Spicer
  - "Hegel and the Understanding of History,", 1970 November 12 (Box-folder 76: 12)
    Speech, University of Ottawa, Canada. Correspondence with William R. Shea
  - "Conquest and Ecumenic Consciousness,", 1971 March 22 (Box-folder 76: 13)
    Speech, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan. Outline
  - "Henry James: The Turn of the Screw," The Southern Review, 1971 Winter
    Includes 1. Prefatory note by Robert Heilman, 2. A letter to Robert Heilman (dated 13 November 1947), 3. Postscript: On Paradise and Revolution (dated January 1970)
    - Typescript (Box-folder 77: 1)
    - Printed copy (Box-folder 77: 2)
    - Correspondence with Robert Heilman, 1969 (Box-folder 77: 3)
  - "From History to Humanity,", 1971 December 2 (Box-folder 77: 4)
    Speech, Louisiana State University in New Orleans, Louisiana. Outline and correspondence with E. Frank Masingill
  - "From History to Humanity--New Problems in the Philosophy of History and Politics,", 1971 December 6 (Box-folder 77: 5)
    Speech, Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, Louisiana. Correspondence with James Babin and Robert A. Pascal
  - Speech, Conference commemorating the 20th anniversary of the publication of The New Science of Politics, University of Notre Dame, South Bend, Indiana, 1972 (Box-folder 77: 6)
    Notes, outline, and transcript
  - "The Reemergence of Gnosticism in Modern Times,", 1972 March 18 (Box-folder 77: 7)
    Speech, The Hartford Seminary Foundation, Hartford, Connecticut. Typewritten transcript from taped presentation and letter from Wayne G. Rollins
  - "Reason as Governor of the Passions,", 1972 March 31 (Box-folder 77: 8)
    Speech, City University of New York. Notes and outline
  - "Notes on Civilization and Foreign Affairs,", 1972 September 5 (Box-folder 77: 9)
    Speech, Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy, Tufts University, Medford, Massachusetts. Typescript and correspondence with Edmund A. Gullion
  - "The Jewish Apocalypse and the Pauline Vision on the Road to Damascus,", 1972 October 31 (Box-folder 77: 10)
    Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Virginia. Outline of seminar
  - "On Classical Studies," Modern Age, 1973 Winter
    - Typescript and printed copy (Box-folder 77: 11)
    - German translation entitled "Uber klassische Studien," Scheidewege, 1973 (Box-folder 77: 12)
  - "Okumenische Menschheit und Friede in der Geschichte,", 1973 November 5 (Box-folder 77: 13)
    Speech, Institut für Friedensforschung, Universität zu Wien, Vienna, Austria. Announcement
  - Order and History, Vol.IV: The Ecumenic Age, 1974
    - Notes and research material (Box-folder 77: 14-18)
    - Outlines (Box-folder 78: 1)
    - Typescript (Box-folder 78: 2-11)
    - Typescript (Box-folder 79: 1-9)
    - Reviews
      - General (Box-folder 79: 10)
      - Altizer, Thomas J. J., "A New History and a New but Ancient God?: A Review-Essay" (Box-folder 79: 11)
        Includes Eric Voegelin's response. Typescript, printed copy, and correspondence with Thomas J. J. Altizer and Ray L. Hart (Journal of the American Academy of Religion)
      - Havard, William C. (Box-folder 79: 12)
    - Spanish translation of introduction (Pedro Félix Hernandez) (Box-folder 79: 13)
  - "Reason: The Classic Experience," The Southern Review, 1974
    - Notes (Box-folder 80: 1)
    - Typescript (Box-folder 80: 2)
    - Printed copy (Box-folder 80: 3)
  - "From History to Humanity,", 1974 March 27 (Box-folder 80: 4)